

+49 163 2255913



dogan.mlevent@gmail.com



mldogan.github.io



Berlin, Germany

### **EDUCATION**

PhD II/2019-present
Technische Universität Berlin

Berlin Mathematical School Phase 2 Subject: Mathematics

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Peter Bürgisser

# Master's Degree 10/2017-11/2019

Technische Universität Berlin Berlin Mathematical School Phase I

Subject: Mathematics Grade: 1.0 (Excellent)

#### Bachelor's Degree 09/2014-08/2017

Middle East Technical University Subject: Mathematics CGPA: 3.99

## **EXPERTISE**

# **Programming Languages**

- Python, C, C++, Java
- SageMath
- Julia
- Macaulay2

#### Languages

- Turkish (native)
- English (fluent)
- German (B2)

# M. Levent Doğan

M.Sc.

#### SUMMARY STATEMENT

I am a PhD student at TU Berlin and a Berlin Mathematical School Phase 2 student. My supervisor is Prof. Dr. Peter Bürgisser.

I am interested in computational problems in the areas of algebra, geometry and combinatorics.

My main research is on geometric complexity theory and geometric invariant theory.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### I) Polynomial Time Algorithms in Invariant Theory for Torus Actions

In 36th Computational Complexity Conference (CCC 2021).

with Peter Bürgisser, Visu Makam, Michael Walter and Avi Wigderson.

DOI: 10.4230/LIPIcs.CCC.2021.32

arXiv: 2102.07727

## 2) The Multivariate Schwartz-Zippel Lemma

In SIAM Journal on Discrete Mathematics. Vol. 36, Iss. 2 (2022).

with Alperen A. Ergür, Jake D. Mundo and Elias Tsigaridas.

DOI: 10.1137/20M1333869

arXiv: 1910.01095

#### **PREPRINTS**

· 2013

#### 3) Deterministic Approximation Algorithms for Volumes of Spectrahedra

with Jonathan Leake and Mohan Ravichandran.

arXiv: 2211.12541

#### 4) On the Complexity of Chow and Hurwitz Forms

with Alperen A. Ergür and Elias Tsigaridas.

Accepted for publication in: ACM Communications in Computer Algebra. arXiv:2202.11582

# GRANTS AND AWARDS

• **2019 - present** ERC Grant 787840

European Union's Horizon 2020 research programme

• 2019 - present Berlin Mathematical School

Admission to Phase 2 studies

• 2017-2019 Berlin Mathematical School

Scholarship for Phase I studies

• 2014-2017 Middle East Technical University and TUBITAK

Scholarship for Science Studies

• 2014 National University Admission Exam

55th place among >1.5 million participants 5th National Human Sciences Olympiads

1st degree for Philosophy

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• 10/2022 - 04/2023 Teaching Assistant

TU Berlin - Algebra I

• 2021 - present Mentor at a Directed Reading Program

I have mentored 3 students at DRP Türkiye

• 2016 Student Assistant

Middle East Technical University

• 2015 Student Assistant

Middle East Technical University

#### RESEARCH VISITS

• I I / 2023 I visited my co-author Michael Walter

Ruhr University Bochum

• 12/2022 I visited my co-author Alperen A. Ergür

University of Texas at San Antonio

• **06/2022** I visited my co-author Michael Walter

Ruhr University Bochum

• **09/2021** I visited my co-author Elias Tsigaridas

Inria Paris

#### CONFERENCES AND TALKS

• 07/2023 SIAM Conference on Applied Algebraic Geometry 2023

Eindhoven

I gave a talk in the minisymposium Efficient Symbolic and

Numerical Algorithms for Polynomial Systems

• **06/2023** Foundations of Computational Mathematics (FOCM) 2023

**Paris** 

• **06/2023** 25th Conference of the International Linear Algebra Society

Madrid

I gave a talk in the minisymposium Semidefinite matrices:

geometry and optimization

• I I / 2022 Dies Mathematicus event

I presented my master's thesis at TU Berlin

• 09/2022 Peterfest: Geometry in Complexity and Computations

Konstanz

• **07/2022** Math+ P-NP event

· 08/2021

I gave a "What is..." seminar talk on the PCP Theorem

• **04/2022** Seminar on Geometry, Probability, and Computing

Talk at the colloquium of University of Texas San Antonio. SIAM Conference on Applied Algebraic Geometry 2021

SIAIT Contended on Applied Algebraic Geometry 2021

I gave a talk at the virtual minisymposium Applied Invariant

Theory: Statistics and Algorithms

• **08/2021** Seminar on Nonlinear Algebra

Leipzig

I gave a talk at the colloquium of MPI MiS

• 07/2021 Computational Complexity Conference 2021

I gave a talk at the virtual conference on the accepted paper Polynomial Time Algorithms in Invariant Theory for Torus

Actions

• 02/2020 Milestone Conference of the Thematic Einstein Semester

Berlin

I gave a talk on my preprint The Multivariate Schwartz-

Zippel Lemma